quitsmokingcommunity.org 2016-05-05

# Privacy Policy - Quit Smoking Community

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Quit Smoking Community, we have a few fundamental principles on privacy:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (Your gender and income level don't matter in your quest to quit smoking!)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for communicating smoking cessation information with you.

Quit Smoking Community (“Quit Smoking Community” or “QSC”) respects your privacy and it is our policy to protect any information we may collect while operating our websites.

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Quit Smoking Community collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Quit Smoking Community’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Quit Smoking Community’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Quit Smoking Community may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Quit Smoking Community also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on WordPress.com blogs. Quit Smoking Community only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Quit Smoking Community’s website choose to interact with Quit Smoking Community in ways that require Quit Smoking Community to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Quit Smoking Community gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account to provide a username and email address. In each case, Quit Smoking Community collects such information only as far as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Quit Smoking Community. Quit Smoking Community does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities such as commenting or participating in surveys and giveaways.

## Aggregated Statistics

Quit Smoking Community may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. Quit Smoking Community may display this information publicly or provide it to others in our effort to be transparent with our users and the community. However, Quit Smoking Community does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Quit Smoking Community discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Quit Smoking Community’s behalf or to provide services available at Quit Smoking Community’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Quit Smoking Community’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Quit Smoking Community will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Quit Smoking Community discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Quit Smoking Community believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Quit Smoking Community, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Quit Smoking Community website and have supplied your email address, Quit Smoking Community may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Quit Smoking Community and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Quit Smoking Community takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Quit Smoking Community uses cookies to help Quit Smoking Community identify and track visitors, their usage of Quit Smoking Community website, and their website access preferences. Quit Smoking Community visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Quit Smoking Community’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Quit Smoking Community’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

## Business Transfers

If Quit Smoking Community, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Quit Smoking Community goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Quit Smoking Community may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

## Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Quit Smoking Community and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Quit Smoking Community may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Quit Smoking Community’s sole discretion. Quit Smoking Community encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a WordPress.com account, you should also check your blog’s dashboard for alerts to these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
